The fantastic tale of his greatest adventure.
Sinbad: Legend of the Seven Seas is a family, animation,
adventure film directed by Tim Johnson.
The sailor of legend is framed by the goddess Eris for the theft of the Book of Peace, and must travel to her realm
at the end of the world to retrieve it and save the life of his childhood friend Prince Proteus.
Sinbad (voice), played by Brad Pitt.
Marina (voice), played by Catherine Zeta-Jones.
Eris (voice), played by Michelle Pfeiffer.
Proteus (voice), played by Joseph Fiennes.
Kale (voice), played by Dennis Haysbert.
Dymas (voice), played by Timothy West.
Sinbad: Legend of the Seven Seas (or simply Sinbad) is a 2003 American animated fantasy adventure film directed
by Tim Johnson and Patrick Gilmore and written by John Logan, featuring the character Sinbad.
Produced by DreamWorks Animation and distributed by DreamWorks Pictures, it stars the voices of Brad
Pitt, Catherine Zeta-Jones, Michelle Pfeiffer, Joseph Fiennes, and Dennis Haysbert.
The film tells the story of Sinbad (voiced by Pitt), a pirate who travels the sea with his dog and his loyal crew, alongside Marina (voiced by Zeta-Jones), the fiancée of his childhood
friend Prince Proteus (voiced by Fiennes), to recover the stolen Book of Peace from Eris (voiced by Pfeiffer) to save Proteus from approving Sinbad's death sentence.
Development began when Ted Elliott and Terry Rossio developed the story of Sinbad in the
vein of the story of Damon and Pythias before settling on a love triangle.
The project was canceled in 1993, though Jeffrey Katzenberg decided to restart some ideas when he left the Walt Disney
Company and co-founded DreamWorks Pictures in 1994 during the production of The Prince of Egypt (1998).
Johnson, who attempted to direct his follow-up CGI animated film Tusker following Antz (1998), before
eventually scrapped the project, was recruited to direct Sinbad and teamed with Gilmore.
Like the studio's previous film, Spirit: Stallion of the Cimarron (2002), the
film combines traditional animation and computer animation.
The film blends elements from One Thousand and One
Nights and classical mythology.
The film's traditional animation and its final line services were provided by Stardust Pictures and Bardel
Entertainment, with PDI/DreamWorks handling its computer animation technology and CG character animation.
The score for the film was composed by Harry Gregson-Williams.
Sinbad was released on July 2, 2003, and received mixed reviews from critics, who praised the animation, action sequences, and
voice performances, but criticized the storyline, polarizing CGI, and the film's departure from its Arabic origin.
Grossing $80 million on a $60 million budget, Sinbad was considered by analysts to be a box-office
failure, causing DreamWorks to suffer a $125 million loss on a string of films.
The film is also listed as one of the biggest box-office bombs
of all time, which nearly bankrupted the studio.
To date, this soon became the final DreamWorks Animation film to use traditional animation
as the studio abandoned and discontinued it in favor of computer animation.
However, DreamWorks brought 2D animation back for the
5-minute short film Bird Karma in 2018.
Until the releases of Rise of the Guardians and Ruby Gillman, Teenage Kraken in 2012 and 2023
respectively, Sinbad: Legend of the Seven Seas was DreamWorks Animation's biggest box office failure.
The film explores themes of prince, water monster,
goddess, sailor, arabian nights.
The tone is lighthearted.